https://www.ocp.org/en-us/privacy-policy

Cart
(0)
Choir Stories
×SHIPPING NOTICE: Product orders and previous orders of missal support materials may be delayed 2–3 weeks after the first Sunday of Advent. Due to processing and shipping delays, orders hoping to be received by Christmas should be placed before 12/7 (standard shipping) or 12/17 (expedited shipping). We apologize for this inconvenience.
×
alternate language
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
OCP is committed to protecting your privacy. The information contained in our privacy policy will help you understand how much personal information is collected on our website and how it is used.
By using our website, you are agreeing to the practices described in this privacy policy. If you feel that our privacy practices are inadequate to protect your privacy, you should refrain from using this website.
We collect information in two different ways: (a) automatically and (b) when you intentionally give it to us or give us permission to obtain it.
Information that Is Automatically Collected
When you visit our website, we may automatically record a variety of general information such as log data your browser sends when you visit a website. This may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, your browser type and settings, what website you came from, the date and time of your request, how you use our website, and cookie data.
We may also collect information about the device you’re using, including the type of device and its operating system, device settings, unique device identifiers and crash data. Check the policies of your device manufacturer and software providers to see what type of information your device makes available to websites.
Like most websites, we use technologies that are small data files placed on your computer or other device that allows us to record certain pieces of information when you visit our website. The specific names and types of the cookies, and other similar technologies we use may change from time to time
About Cookies
A cookie is a small text file that is transferred to your browser by a web server and allows a website to recognize a particular device or browser. This lets a website remember a user's preferences or lets a user remain signed in to a website or view products that were placed in a shopping cart. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, but they generally allow you to view, disable or delete browser cookies, accept or reject cookies, and notify a user each time a cookie is offered. Note that disabling cookies or deleting information from cookies may interfere with the performance and features of our website.
About Google Analytics
Our website uses Google Analytics. To learn about how Google uses the data it collects, see "How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps."
We may use automatically collected information to analyze your use of our website, to improve our website, products and services, and to assist us with marketing and messaging, as well as to offer you customized content (for instance, suggesting products you may be interested in).
Information You Give Us or Give Us Permission to Obtain
When you sign up to receive our email newsletters, sign up for an account, or order products/services through our website, you voluntarily give us certain information, such as your name, username, email address, physical address, telephone number, and payment information.
You may also provide us with personal information when you post comments or reviews on our website. These comments/reviews and any personal information you submit in connection with those comments/reviews may be available to the public.
You may also give us permission to access your information held by other services, such as when you share our website through your social media accounts (e.g., Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and Reddit). Also, these services may collect information about your use of our website. You should check the settings and privacy policies of any such service you’re using to see what it shares with us and what information it collects.
We use the personal information you provide us to identify you when you sign into your account and to administer your account; to provide you with requested products and services; to send you emails you have requested; to communicate with you in response to your questions and comments; to post comments and reviews you submit; to analyze your use of our website to improve our website, products and services; and to communicate with you about your orders.
Security and Storage
We use reasonable physical, technical and administrative measures to safeguard information in our possession against loss and theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure and use. For example, when you place an order for a product, our secure server software (SSL) encrypts the information you input before it is sent to us.
No security measures are perfect, though, and you may want to review the FTC website suggestions for protecting yourself from identify theft.
We currently store information on both our own servers and third party servers based in the United States. We reserve the right to change location and server providers without notice. If you are visiting our website from outside of the United States of America, by using our website, you agree that information may be transferred to, stored or processed in the United States.
How We Share Information
With a few exceptions (described below), we don’t sell, trade or rent your personal information to others. We do share information:
With Your Consent.
We may share your personal information when you authorize us to share it with third parties, such as social networking sites or PayPal.
As Necessary to Provide Services.
We will share your personal information with third parties when it’s necessary to provide our services. For instance, our email newsletters and updates are sent through MailChimp and ClickDimensions, products may be shipped through a distributor, and payments may be made through PayPal. Further, some rights owners may be provided with certain information in connection with their licensing arrangements.
In Connection with a Sale of Assets.
In the event of a sale of all or part of our assets, merger, or reorganization, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy, we may transfer information from or about you to one or more third parties as part of that transaction.
To Comply with Laws and Protect Rights.
We reserve the right to disclose personal information when we believe that we should do so in order to comply with the law or legal process, to prevent fraud or to protect the rights of OCP or third parties.
What Choices Do You Have about Your Information?
Email Addresses
We know that the members of our email list are sensitive to receiving unwanted email, so, at any time, you may choose to not be included in e-mail messages from OCP by unsubscribing your e-mail address. If you opt out, you will still receive emails relating to your account and purchases.
Account Information
If you have created an account on our website, you may access and update the information you have provided us at any time by clicking Welcome, (Name) and then Account Details in the dropdown menu.
Do Not Track Signals.
Some web browsers have a “Do Not Track” feature, which lets you tell websites you visit that you don’t want to have your online activity tracked. Our website is not set up to respond to those signals.
Browser Settings.
The browser you use may allow you to control cookies or other types of local data storage.
Mobile Device Settings.
Your mobile device may allow you to control whether certain types of information are shared with us.
Minors’ Personal Information
Our website is not intended for use by those under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18 or if you discover that your minor child has shared personal information with us without your consent, please contact us [link] to request removal of specific content or information that has been publicly posted. Note that such a request does not ensure complete removal of the posted content or information and that there may be circumstances in which the law does not require or allow the requested removal.
Additional Information
When required by law, we will, upon your request, provide you with a copy of the personal information we hold, provided that you pay the current fee (which will not exceed the amount set by law).
To obtain additional information about our privacy policy, contact:
5536 NE Hassalo, Portland, OR, 97213-3638
liturgy@ocp.org
Updates
We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by email to you at the last email address you provided us, by posting notice of such changes on our sites and applications, or by other means, consistent with applicable law.
Date of Last Update: July 2018
